{"name": "70B  2014-10 Asia", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. Rafi has 2 cellular phone plans to choose from. Plan A costs $69.99 per month and includes all long-distance calls. Plan B costs $49.99 per month and costs $0.10 per minute for long-distance calls. Plan A and Plan B would cost the same amount for a month in which Rafi has how many minutes of long-distance cellular phone calls?", "choices": {"A": "20", "B": "200", "C": "210", "D": "220", "E": "1,200"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. Melanie noticed that about 15% of her monthly paycheck goes toward taxes. Her paycheck, before taxes, was $3, 200 this month. About how much money from this paycheck went toward taxes?", "choices": {"A": "$48", "B": "$213", "C": "$480", "D": "$2,720", "E": "$3,185"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. In \u25b3ABC, the sum of the measures of\u2220A and \u2220B is 74\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220C?", "choices": {"A": "16\u00b0", "B": "32\u00b0", "C": "74\u00b0", "D": "106\u00b0", "E": "148\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. For the list of numbers below, which value is greater, the mean or the median, and what is its value?                   73, 78, 87, 89, 93", "choices": {"A": "Median; 87", "B": "Median; 93", "C": "Mean; 73", "D": "Mean; 84", "E": "Mean; 93"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane. A has coordinates (-5, -3). Point A is translated 5 units to the left and 3 units down and labeled A'. What are the coordinates of A'?", "choices": {"A": "(-10, -6)", "B": "(-8, -8)", "C": "(-5, -6)", "D": "(0, 0)", "E": "(10, 6)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to (-2x)(-2x)(-2x) ?", "choices": {"A": "-6x", "B": "-6x3", "C": "-8x", "D": "-8x3", "E": "8x3"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. What id the solution to the equation 2x - 5 + 3x = 11 - x + 2x ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "4", "E": "8"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. When x = -2, what is the value of 3x2 + 2x - 3 ? ", "choices": {"A": "-19", "B": "-11", "C": "-7", "D": "5", "E": "13"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. A company produces a snack package called Snackinz. Each Snackinz package contains exactly 2 cheese wedges, 1 container of yogurt, and pound of crackers. The company has in storage 600 cheese wedges, 350 containers of yogurt, and 100 pounds of crackers. Using only what the company has in storage, what is the maximum number of Snackinz packages that can be produced?", "choices": {"A": "25", "B": "100", "C": "300", "D": "350", "E": "400"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. Sylvia, Carlos, and Linda have a 60-square-foot garden in their backyard. Carlos plans  of the garden with beans and Linda plants  of the garden with corn. Sylvia plants the remaining portion of the garden with carrots. How many square feet of the garden does Sylvia plant with carrots?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "10", "C": "15", "D": "20", "E": "30"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. Lines m and n are cut by transversal l in the figure below. There are 8 angles labeled. Which of the following congruence statements must be true?", "choices": {"A": "\u22201 \u22204", "B": "\u22201 \u22205", "C": "\u22201 \u22208", "D": "\u22204 \u22205", "E": "\u22204 \u22206"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. In the Clydestown mayoral election, Stella McBride received 610 more votes than Jared Youngblood. McBride and Youngblood received a total of 4,618 votes. Which of the following systems of equations, when solved, gives the number of votes McBride received (M) and the number of vote Youngblood received (Y)?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "-7", "B": "-5", "C": "5", "D": "7", "E": "19"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. In the standard (x, y ) coordinate plane, the equation of a circle is x2 + y2 = 144. At what 2 points does the circle intersect the y-axis?", "choices": {"A": "(0, 12) and (0, -12)", "B": "(0, 24) and (0, -24)", "C": "(0, 72) and (0, -72)", "D": "(0, 144) and (0, -144)", "E": " (0, 288) and (0, -288)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15.  A store owner bought 20 dozen toy boats at a cost of $2.00 per dozen. She sold all the toy boats in one day for $0.50 each. What was her profit?", "choices": {"A": "$80.00", "B": "$120.00", "C": "$160.00", "D": "$240.00", "E": "$480.00"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. A farmer is planning to build a horizontal bridge across a circular pond that has a radius of 30 feet. The flat bridge will be on a diameter and will extend 5 feet past the pond at each end. What will be the length, in feet, of the bridge?", "choices": {"A": "35", "B": "40", "C": "60", "D": "65", "E": "70"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. In the equation , x = ?", "choices": {"A": "-1", "B": "1", "C": "4", "D": "16", "E": "32"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. Jones County High School is building an entrance ramp into the Technical Skills Building for a new motorcycle repair class. As shown in the figure below, the upper end of the ramp will be 5 feet above level ground. The local building code has a requirement that the ramp have a maximum slope of . To meet the building code's requirement, what must be the minimum distance, in feet, of the lower end of the ramp from the building?", "choices": {"A": "9", "B": "15", "C": "16", "D": "20", "E": "25"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. The ratio of the side lengths of 2 similar triangles is 2: 3. The perimeter of the smaller triangle is 16 meters. What is the perimeter, in meters, of the larger triangle?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "24", "C": "", "D": "36", "E": "48"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. What is the next term after  in the geometric sequence 20, -10, 5, , ...?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "0", "C": "", "D": "1", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. At the Pirate's Vessel Miniature Golf Park, a life-size mechanical pirate shouts \"Ahoy, matey! \" once every 6 minutes exactly. A mechanical parrot sitting on the pirates shoulder squawks once every 8 minutes exactly. At 3: 00 p.m., the pirate shouts and the parrot squawks at the same time. What is the next time they will shout and squawk at the same time?", "choices": {"A": "3:12 p.m.", "B": "3:14 p.m.", "C": "3:16 p.m.", "D": "3:24 p.m.", "E": "3:48 p.m."}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. The figure below shows trapezoid ABCD. The shorter parallel side is extended to indicate the altitude of ABCD. The given dimensions are in decimeters. What is the area, in square decimeters, of ABCD?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "28", "C": "40", "D": "50", "E": "56"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. To solve the equation (x + 2)(x - 3) = 14, Addy first manipulates it so that she has an equivalent equation that is a quadratic expression set equal to 0. Which of the following equations could be Addy's?", "choices": {"A": "2x - 15 = 0", "B": "x2 -20 = 0", "C": "x2 + 5x -20 = 0", "D": "x2 - x + 8 = 0", "E": "x2 - x - 20 = 0 "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. The expression (x2 - 3x - 4) - (-x2 + 3x - 3) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "-1", "B": "2x2 - 7 ", "C": "2x2 - 1 ", "D": "2x2 - 6x - 7 ", "E": "2x2 - 6x - 1"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. Soccer is a game where the main objective for each team is to score points by shooting a ball into the opposing teams goal. Shots on goal (S) is the number of attempts a team makes to shoot the ball into the goal. Goals scored (G) is the number of shots on goal that are successful. Which of the following expressions give the percent of shots on goal that are goals scored?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. A small square has an area of 16 square inches. A large square has an area that is 128 square inches greater than that of the small square. Which of the following lengths, in inches, is closest to the side length of the large square?", "choices": {"A": "8.5", "B": "10.6", "C": "11.3", "D": "12.0", "E": "15.3"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. Use the following information to answer question 27-30.The function f and g are defined as f(x) = x + 2 and g(x) = 3x + 8 . The lines representing the 2 functions are shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below.27. What is f(-8) ?", "choices": {"A": "-16", "B": "-10", "C": "-6", "D": "2", "E": "10"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Use the following information to answer question 27-30.The function f and g are defined as f(x) = x + 2 and g(x) = 3x + 8 . The lines representing the 2 functions are shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below.28. For what value of x does f(x) = g(x) ?", "choices": {"A": "-5", "B": "-3", "C": "", "D": "-2", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Use the following information to answer question 27-30.The function f and g are defined as f(x) = x + 2 and g(x) = 3x + 8 . The lines representing the 2 functions are shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below.29. Which of the following expression is equivalent to g(f(x)) ?", "choices": {"A": "4x + 10", "B": "3x + 10", "C": "3x + 14", "D": "3x2 + 16", "E": "3x2 + 14x + 16"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. Use the following information to answer question 27-30.The function f and g are defined as f(x) = x + 2 and g(x) = 3x + 8 . The lines representing the 2 functions are shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below.30. Comparison of the rates at which the values of f(x) and of g(x) increase as the value of x increases shows that the value of f(x) increases\uff1a", "choices": {"A": " as fast as the value of g(x).", "B": " as fast as the value of g(x).", "C": "at the same rate as the value of g(x).", "D": "3 times as fast as the value of g(x).", "E": "4 times as fast as the value of g(x)."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. Adam, Brenda, and Nimai were hired to mow a neighbor's lawn. Since there was only 1 lawnmower, they agreed to divide the money received in the same proportion as the time each spent mowing the lawn. Brenda mowed 5 minutes longer than Adam, and Nimai mowed 15 minutes less than Adam. If it took the 3 of them a total of 80 minutes to mow the lawn, what percent of the money did Adam receive?", "choices": {"A": "25.0%", "B": "26.7%", "C": "33.3%", "D": "37.5%", "E": "75.0%"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Which of the following has the greatest value?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": " ", "E": "81% of 1"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33.  As shown below, a straight slide in a water park is 42 feet long and is built over a distance of 39 feet along level ground. Which of the following expressions equals the measure of the acute angle that the slide makes with the ground?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Use the following information to answer question 34-36.The dartboard below consists of 5 regions bordered by concentric circles. The innermost region has a radius of r centimeters. Each of the 4 outer regions has uniform width r centimeters. Shown within each region is the number of points awarded (10, 8, 6, 4, or 1) to a player whose thrown dart sticks into that region. A player is awarded 0 points for any dart that does not stick into the board.In the dart game played on this dartboard, players take turns throwing 1 round consisting of 3 consecutive throws by 1 player. A player's 1-round point total is the sum of the point values awarded for the throws in that round. The first player to accumulate at least 75 points is the winner of the dart game; the winner need not complete his or her final round.34. Assume that a dart, when thrown, will stick into a random point on the dartboard. What is the probability that the dart will stick into the 10-point region?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. Use the following information to answer question 34-36.The dartboard below consists of 5 regions bordered by concentric circles. The innermost region has a radius of r centimeters. Each of the 4 outer regions has uniform width r centimeters. Shown within each region is the number of points awarded (10, 8, 6, 4, or 1) to a player whose thrown dart sticks into that region. A player is awarded 0 points for any dart that does not stick into the board.In the dart game played on this dartboard, players take turns throwing 1 round consisting of 3 consecutive throws by 1 player. A player's 1-round point total is the sum of the point values awarded for the throws in that round. The first player to accumulate at least 75 points is the winner of the dart game; the winner need not complete his or her final round.35. Which of the following values is NOT possible for a 1-round point total for 1 player?", "choices": {"A": "20", "B": "21", "C": "22", "D": "23", "E": "24"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Use the following information to answer question 34-36.The dartboard below consists of 5 regions bordered by concentric circles. The innermost region has a radius of r centimeters. Each of the 4 outer regions has uniform width r centimeters. Shown within each region is the number of points awarded (10, 8, 6, 4, or 1) to a player whose thrown dart sticks into that region. A player is awarded 0 points for any dart that does not stick into the board.In the dart game played on this dartboard, players take turns throwing 1 round consisting of 3 consecutive throws by 1 player. A player's 1-round point total is the sum of the point values awarded for the throws in that round. The first player to accumulate at least 75 points is the winner of the dart game; the winner need not complete his or her final round.36. What is the minimum number of the throws a player must make in order to win the dart game?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "7", "C": "8", "D": "9", "E": "10"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Consider all the rectangles with a perimeter of 36 feet and side lengths that are integer numbers of feet. What is the maximum area, in square feet, of any such rectangle?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "9", "C": "18", "D": "36", "E": "81"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. All 10-digit satellite telephone numbers for a certain company begin with the same 6-digit sequence 810-786. Each of the remaining 4 digits can be any of the 10 possible digits. How many possible satellite telephone numbers are there for this company?", "choices": {"A": "44", "B": "6(104)", "C": "104", "D": "9(109)", "E": "1010"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39.  Which of the following is the solution set for the equation ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. The amount of money, A dollars, in a savings account t years after the initial deposit of P dollars is given by the function A(t) = Pe0.08t. Which of the following expressions gives the value of t for which A(t) = 2P ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "4", "C": "8", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. A cube of clay was reshaped into a rectangular prism that is 24 inches long, 24 inches wide, and  inch high. Assume that no clay was lost in the reshaping. Which of the following values is closest to the side length; in inches, that the cube had?", "choices": {"A": "3.6", "B": "6.0", "C": "7.8", "D": "9.0", "E": "14.7"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Twice a number is 7 greater than  of the same number. What is the number?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. The parabola in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below has vertex (4, -5) and y-intercept (0, 11). Which of the following could be an equation of this parabola?", "choices": {"A": "y = (x - 4)2", "B": "y = (x - 4)2 + 5", "C": "y = (x - 4)2 - 5", "D": "y = (x - 4)2 + 11", "E": "y = (x - 4)2 - 11"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. One of the following graphs in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane represents the solution set to the system below. Which graph is it?               y \u2265 |x| - 2               y \u2264 4", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. Suppose that \u25b3PQR has an area of A square inches and that the vertices of \u25b3STU are the midpoints of the sides of \u25b3PQR. In terms of A, what is the area of \u25b3STU in square inches?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "2A", "E": "4A"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46.  Shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below are 2 angles. The measure of \u2220POR is d\u00b0, the measure of \u2220POQ is (11d)\u00b0, and the point R, O, and Q are collinear. What is the value of d? ", "choices": {"A": "7.5", "B": "9", "C": "15", "D": "18", "E": "30"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. What is the perimeter, in feet, of the figure shown below?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "21", "C": "22", "D": "23", "E": "24"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. Max's design for a rectangular stained glass window with 7 triangles is shown below. The 2 white triangles are congruent (\u25b3ABC\u25b3DEC) and will be a different color than the other 5 triangles. The design includes the measures of \u2220CAB\uff0c\u2220ACB\uff0cand \u2220DCE. Max can find the measure of \u2220BCE with which of the following additional pieces of information?", "choices": {"A": "The measure of \u2220ABC", "B": "The measure of \u2220ABE", "C": "The measure of \u2220CDE", "D": "The length of BC", "E": "The length of DE"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. The function f(x) graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below represents the function y = sin x after a translation, a vertical stretch, and a horizontal shrink. Point A is a maximum point and B is a minimum point. What is the period of f(x)?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. Triangle \u25b3ABC is graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. Point C is on BD, AB = AD, and AC = . What are the coordinate of A?(Note: AB means the distance from A to B.)", "choices": {"A": "(8, 18)", "B": "(8, 24)", "C": "(10, 18)", "D": "(12, 20)", "E": "(12, 24)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Each point on a line in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane is equidistant from (7, 3) and (-3, 3). Which of the following is an equation of that line?", "choices": {"A": "x = 0", "B": "x = 2", "C": "x = 3", "D": "x = 4", "E": "x = 10"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. In the figure below, square ABCD has a side length of 6 inches, AC is a diagonal, and \u2220AEC measures 120\u00b0. What is the length, in inches, of CE?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "6"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53.  In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, the line 2x + y = 5 is reflected across the x-axis. What is the y-intercept of the resulting line?", "choices": {"A": "-5", "B": "-2", "C": "2", "D": "", "E": "5"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. In the figure shown below, B is between A and D, the length of AB is 30 miles, the length of BC is 40 miles, and the measure of \u2220CBD is 60\u00b0. To the nearest mile, what is the length of AC ?(Note: sin60\u00b0=sin120\u00b0\u22480.866; cos60\u00b0=0.5; cos120\u00b0=-0.5)(Note: For a triangle with sides of length a\uff0c b, and c that are opposite \u2220A\uff0c\u2220B\uff0cand \u2220C, respectively\uff0cc2 = a2 + b2- 2ab cos C, and .)", "choices": {"A": "36", "B": "46", "C": "50", "D": "61", "E": "78"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. A car travels east at an average speed of 70 miles per hour for 2 hours, and then travels north at an average speed of 50 miles per hour for 1 hour. The diagram below shows the position, P, of the car at the end of the trip, relative to its starting position, O. To the nearest whole degree, what is the measure of \u2220NOP ?(Note: ; ; )", "choices": {"A": "15\u00b0", "B": "20\u00b0", "C": "21\u00b0", "D": "69\u00b0", "E": "70\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. If the inequality mx - m \uff1e18 has the solution set 7}\\right\\}\">, then m = ?", "choices": {"A": "-12", "B": "3", "C": "11", "D": "12", "E": "25"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. Given that x is a prime number greater than 7, which of the following values of y will guarantee that 4x + yx is divisible by 7?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "7", "C": "11", "D": "28", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. For all real numbers w, x, y, and z, the determinant of one of the following matrices is equal to twice the determinant of . Which matrix?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. Given that (a + b) \uff1e 0 and (a2 - b2) \uff1e 0, which of the following statements must be true?", "choices": {"A": "a&lt;0 and b&lt;0", "B": "a&gt;0 and b&gt;0", "C": "a=0 or b=0", "D": "(a - b) &lt; 0", "E": "(a - b) &gt; 0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. For  to be true for all positive real numbers x, y, and z, it is sufficient to know that a = ?", "choices": {"A": "-3", "B": "3", "C": "-d + 3", "D": "d - 3", "E": "d + 3"}, "correct": "E"}]}